David Cole Senior Front end Developer

✓ david.web.dev.116@gmail.com

Polish

davidcole_96390

Podchorążych 01A/15, 22-721 Płazów

S live:.cid.1a7ab701f5201e0b

https://github.com/WebDev116

Summary

Passionate Front-End Developer with over +7 years of experience in web development.Planned, developed, tested, deployed and maintained web applications. Proficient in various platforms, languages, and embedded systems. Effectively translated client requirements into application designs and systems requirements. Followed policies and procedures related to application methods and quality standards at all times. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Professional Experience

2022/01 - 2023/12

Netcotech, Edmonton, Candad

Senior Front End Developer

- Working in rapid, fast-paced development environment with having setup and built data-intensive web-based platforms from scratch for market indices, fund analysis, and asset valuation.
- Working closely with finance research engineers to transform terabyte-scale data from multiple sources into user understandable dashboards.
- Setup foundation of boilerplate (React + Redux Saga + Ant Design) to be used across all existing tools and upcoming tools.
- Drove initiative and implemented Identity Access and Management module for client permissions

2020/10 – 2022/04 upwork, freelancer

Junior Front End Developer

- Participated in development of a well responsive single page application using AngularJS framework and JavaScript in conjunction with HTML5, CSS3 standards.
- Developed custom web application interfaces using HTML and CSS to meet the requirements of the client.
- Responsible for architecting and executing solutions using JavaScript frameworks like React.js, Angular.js and Backbone.js.
- Develop various screens for the front end using React JS and used various predefined components from NPM (Node Package Manager) and Redux library.

2018/05 - 2020/12 TechnoImpact, Melbourn, Australia

Junior Front End Developer

- Converted a Figma design into HTML pages using React, React Native, Angular, Vue, HTML, CSS while closely working with designers.
- Building websites and apps that responsive and usable.
- Worked closely with programmers and clients to meet project requirements, goals, and desired functionality

2017/08 - 2018/04 Upwork.com

Freelancer

- Provided extensive technical support to the customer which boosted company profit margins by 20%.
- Improved my knowledgeable of the programming.
- Good Chance of improved my skill from beginner to expert.

Education

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of the computer science

1 Maja 50, 40-287 Katowice, Poland

University of Economics of Katowice

Skills

- Programming Languages

JavaScript / TypeScript

Golang

• C,C++ / C#

- Back End

Node.js

Golang

Express.js

- Front End

● HTML, CSS, BootStrap

JavasSript frameworks

(React.js, React-Native, Next.js, Vue.js, Angular)

CSS frameworks (Tailwind CSS)

Team & Agile Collaboration

Git

DevOps

OCI/CD

Unit Test

Languages

English

• • • •

0 0

Polish

• • •

Projects

Hotel Booking System

Role: Front End Developer

Teach Stack: React.js, Golang, Postgres

RotationPlus https://rotationsplus.com

Role: Front End developer

Teach Stack: React.js, Node.js(Strapi), Postgres

Travel Booking SystemRole: Front End developer

Teach Stack: React.js, React-Native, PHP/Laravel

CRM System for Car Warranty/Repair

Role: Front End developer

Teach Stack: Angular 6.0, React-Native, Firebase, Amazon S3

https:/tripshop.com

https://room-res.com

https://www.auwarranties.co.uk

STRENGTH

Collaborative

Always keen to share my knowledge, help, discuss, teach and learn from others. Able to collaborate with cross-functional teams to create a high-quality end product.

Result-oriented

Many confuse progress with moving in the right direction. I always make sure to check if the team is on the right path.

Project management and prioritization

Before starting a new project, I always set time aside to have the entire team go through the tasks, prioritize them and assign a due date to make sure deadlines are promptly met.